<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on RedGreen Studio</title>
    <link>http://redgreen.studio/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on RedGreen Studio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, RedGreen Studio; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:38:01 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://redgreen.studio/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple file caching &amp; manipulation in iOS</title>
      <link>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2017/08/20/simple-file-cache-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:38:01 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2017/08/20/simple-file-cache-ios/</guid>
      <description>This document is heavily influenced by Apple docs
 (Jump: Browse to the sample code on Github)
For security purposes, an iOS app’s interactions with the file system are limited to the directories inside the app’s sandbox directory. During installation of a new app, the installer creates a number of container directories for the app inside the sandbox directory. Each container directory has a specific role. The bundle container directory holds the app’s bundle, whereas the data container directory holds data for both the app and the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic view push for UITextField in iOS</title>
      <link>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2017/05/14/ios-uitextfield-automatic-view-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 14:46:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2017/05/14/ios-uitextfield-automatic-view-push/</guid>
      <description>Client: I can enter my first name, middle name and last name fine in iPhone 7, but in iPhone 5S the last name text field is covered by keyboad, why this is happening? One of the oldest and basic problem of using UITextField in iOS. If you are making a form or adding multiple UI components in one page for your iOS application, its pretty much normal that the bottom UITextFields could be covered by your keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBLocationManager for iOS, simple yet powerfull</title>
      <link>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2017/03/21/bblocationmanager-simple-yet-powerfull/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:44:09 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2017/03/21/bblocationmanager-simple-yet-powerfull/</guid>
      <description>Location services is a powerful feature of iOS, but sometimes its not easy to understand all the API&amp;rsquo;s and learn how to use them. With BBLocationManager, you can start using iOS Location Services API in no time. It provides good code documentation for better understanding of the methods and delegates. If you are making a location aware app or building a geofencing app like the Alarm app in iOS which reminds you to buy milk when you are near home, BBLocationManager can be your choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronus Code Execution in iOS</title>
      <link>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2016/12/26/synchronus-code-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 16:49:03 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2016/12/26/synchronus-code-ios/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Asynchronus programming&amp;rdquo; is a polular term now-a-days. People are talking all over the internet about it. Specially when we have network/API calls, we should keep free the main thread, and do the network calling stuff in the background. Cause if we block the main thread, it won&amp;rsquo;t be able to respond to user interaction such as touch. Async calls can be executed on new/seperate threads synchronously, or can be scheduled in the main/other thread&amp;rsquo;s runloop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShellMamu, Shell Utility Tool</title>
      <link>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2016/11/12/shell-mamu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 21:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redgreen.studio/blog/2016/11/12/shell-mamu/</guid>
      <description>ShellMamu is a small utility/helper tool for shell scripting language. It offers some utility commands which I used frequently in my work. The main purpose of shellMamu is to easily provide the needed parameters for a command.
This document is a brief primer on using shellMamu. Please visit the github page for more details.
    Background I&amp;rsquo;ve been using small shell/unix commands for various purpose in Mac&amp;rsquo;s terminal for years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>